Welcome back we're alive twenty fifteen addition of
build I'm here with some fabulous people why don't you introduce
yourselves and tell us what you do we'll start over here and my name is
wentworth I'm program manage on the...thank also advisory council member of the and foundation
you are really interesting activity from florida or something close...the weather is almost identical in germany to
...germany I it's a little off the.
Apartment so I martin would have done the execdirector dot net foundation
...eight-day overt its of the james bond both
...messy imax technical evangelist for the...foundation got and I'm
...a director program management for the net team as well as the president...
my goodness I...we should get your chair...the...unknown on let's start
with this obvious question what is the dot abpfoundation why do
...what I can...that one I mean so we create that...a year-ago and,
we're really looking you do was create an independent entity
that would allow us to kind of bring together and continue to foster a lot
of the open-source innovation...happening around dot net...bring it together into one
...more cohesive community...more cohesive ecosystem as a developer
...the microsoft ecosystem what does that mean for me.
It means...bunch of stuff now is opensource that you're using the old...
what you'll using set at you dot net core...compiler roslyn
everything there is now all...if you want to go see what's happening you just go in a
...to get hope go check out the actual oscilloscope...then...you know,
you find an issue with the library leno's you know, that before when I had a real job before kids with
...microsoft...I went and found...issue with like the dictionary class...they see and
...then my way of fixing that was...login through connect...and, then like
...the bug...get it rejected and then come back and say no, israel
...I'll say I'll say defect scribe the
...can understand what I say as...valuable moi?
...sony do ...you get a defective things...system, you know,
...class here's the issue with it and you can raise an issue on get hope we can have a
...the develop as a right there checking in and out code every
day...issue and you can...even come in and say well actually this is what I think is the fix,
you know, his I think this code...be fix and the guys who work on the team can take a look about fix and
say up bellows good we'll check it in and then, you know,
the night-vision studio twenty fifteen comes out worlds and updates windows
...fixed note that there's a big difference between
open-source jan and source...talk about the distinction and
...talk about what which one we are a dot abpfoundation so, yeah, I'm I think that
...openness they just think that microsoft...for a couple of years now so we always had like some projects
were license on open-source license which
basically means in theory you can take care of you want so that's great but the differences that
the team itself still lives in this redman area behind the
...star...you don't see what's happening, yeah, every once in awhile would come out drop some source
...the...and all the way that works is we actually on get up so as...said like
...literally working there so...cody...our team and we all...views but,
impassive always private internal...now they just normal...requests
...get up so it's a martin...on the same...and...submit something it does...
view...submits as a...for some get up so the team members can comment on that and say
...you completely screwed up that line over here right but they really amazing pieces that not just weaken comment on
...community can also common so from all point of view...they you...external
...once submitted change are you an internal by you...view it's the same process so we all
playing the same sandbox and that basically also means that we make contributors
way more successful because we give you the context that you need in order to be successful
...the whole tribe and others that we have about how the dc architected why does
...that was previously just implementation details...you...to knowledge as works but if you want
to have to you want to contribute to that...say poured the...or freebie is the as it happened a
couple weeks ago you have to know all the secret sauce as well you can just
say all according...the and it's just magic and happens to work as if...one of the
...make that magic work galaxy have to deal with that.
That's awesome so I think the take away from that as you announced the next version of the best stars coming out
...so...serious note what projects are there in
the dot abpfoundation and how does someone sort of become part of a dot
...project...corrupt some of the proxiesyeah,
we have a ton of projects...foundation I think there's over thirty five of them now and,
they're not all just microsoft right they're not all just microsoft we have a lot of projects
that contributed...and...other companies rocco and
...texture so it's the foundation is not just about
like legal protection either it's about like, you know, it's about a...abouts it,
you know, say hey we have like a really good model for doing
opensource how do we create these practices best practices for all of
...all of these projects within the foundation...easy...projects...get access services that
we've set up...we've set up fora thirty-five projects audrey ban,
you know, allow the projects to come in and start to
use those services right today just go to the done at foundation gold website
...dot that foundation the old website and...
eating visit f guarantees you know-how to joy and just come along and contact us them getting
search out it probably...and...email about it and get stuff so I will tell you
...lives so make sure you ask questions and have them come in otherwise I'm just going to
ask whatever I want and that also works too so
...other question I had was say I'm a developer that
doesn't open-source project how do I make that part of the dot net
foundation or is it something I want to do why would I want to do it what would be the process?
This though we can add that projects of a we can you just put your source code is
...unite as a primary goal is to make
...have a strong ecosystem around open-source
...developers...make it open that's...your job number-one
...opensource now great and...if you want to compile the foundation
...I go to dot net foundation the old website and the contact us...getting
...we also go three light, you know, what you do you want to be part of foundation what city
...that's the thing what the pros and cons...a foundation
and...it...enough to have...so I love that so say I have a really good dot net
open-source project what would be the compelling reasons why I should say, you know,
what I should consider joining the dot abpfoundation the may be the main thing is
...it's about we can help you scale...light is a bunch of stuff which is an
engineer you don't in a...we want to have to worry about, you know, like blah-blah-blah
...blah-blah-blah jan asI...itself my...something technical but
...blah-blah-blah...I should we have...you should be make people
...out full when they contributing some things that we can we've got some light legal sign-off
for them and do we do those sorts of things we can help you there we can provide a said, you know,
help you...administration over-the-board stuffy that would you can sort of
...on the code we can help you when it comes the marketing you'll project, you know,
we can promote your project things like that, you know,...out, you know, we providing a isset
...back-to-back and services that you might be like you need help with build infrastructure, you know,
turns out we know kuala paper with some...in a cloud some and...
so we can help you get the...need...you access to bigger community
right, you know, I mean that's like the key like having all these projects and abpfoundation acted talk to each
other's much about...best practices but it's also about eating developers, you know,
that art...working on similar things across projects like, you know,
you know what you broadcast...that's what you...is that it's really
I think that the number one thing that...bring right now is just visibility
...both visibility amongst other dot net developers
are interested in participating contributing...your project helping you with
it but also visibility...developers that are going to take advantage and use that project as part
of...applications that's...we talked open-source...that is usually the number one thing they're looking
for just help with promoting invisibility to what they're working on got it
so we do have some questions how would you compare this foundation to how...is maintain
...know a lot about job as me plane but I can start and...and I think there's a couple interesting
think the first that are important think about for there's the dot abpfoundation and
we talk about governance and things like that we're really talking about the boring aspect of how
the foundation itself is run...a unique aspect of the way we approach
that abpfoundation as we don't get in...mess around with the projects unite the
projects determine how they're going to govern themselves what model they're going to use those kind of things
we have people available we have advisory council available to help right if you're not sure which
way to use which approach to take which direction to go...project but the project is owned by the
project donor...so separating...dot abpfoundation from dot net itself is an
important thing so that net as a set of projects then have a governance model around
and, those are still owned by the owners of the...net projects they determine the direction of it
...the course for how they're going to go and manage the
open-source development of dot net and that's the part that is more analogous to the way job of
...java has a project...and...it really take a...hand
in the direction of java so you don't you don't necessarily want to dictate the direction
of the os project you output...the project explicitly do not want to degraded is a
budget that day are a community, you know, they all the projects and what we want to do is help
get...hands-on keyboards help contribution to that projects got
a question from andrew that which is probably one of the most important where can I get that
dot net...
And, yeah, I think we like what they were swarmed like literally I was
...all right so...how is the work regressing on the ecma standard for
the latest version of csharp is csharp one of the project
in the dot abpfoundation the at the roslyn project
...compiler project for csharp anybody that is one of the projects in the foundation my
practice actually...earlier in february we had an interesting milestone
...as the dot net team die right now we're
...milestone where we actually now have.
Runtime framework based on that layer any framework layer and
compilers stack for...core pipe all opensource on get hubs that's the whole
...a lot of them...of food.
The yeah, that's cool all right so the question will
...crappy open-source and written in dot net as...a that would be a
...here's the thing I think I think that reason to relieve the fact that the
dot abpfoundation isn't inline to tell people what to do
and you're sort of inline sort of put that these protected put these protective service on and help them
...been censorship...I've got...light on the...accounts, you know,
people like normal and...always people who got tons of
...opensource dot net it's about bringing these guys together
in goes together and helping everybody contribution get better at doing...important actually
...note that write the foundation is like it's really a out the community
helping us build this together right it's not just microsoft and ossie...we work
from microsoft or part of it but the advisory council most of the members are just part of
that community right so that's important so here's a question how is the
foundations structured and I know we've talked about like a set of services that you that you do
provide the projects what are those explicitly what would be those things
so structure and services...as far as a projects concern they probably don't care
...stoops agencies again blah-blah-blah...blah but it's an independent
...foundation...I'm company it's got a board of directors
...j...and michael dec asset the role of directors of the
...of that company and then on the executive direct...bets officially the company
...england
...got roles in the company and we have the advisory council who again,
from the community and they play the lead role in like deciding
what governance models we want to have how we want to help projects and things but as a as a project
...you don't really care we just we just there as a company
...and can exist on your behalf to help you with your project to bring more bring more
hans to keyboards to help you get more successful let's talk a little about how you
helped bring the hands to keyboard in this project anybody have any input on that?
Well, I mean as martin said I mean the first thing is you need to
open-source your project right I mean that's to me the most important
stab and anybody who doesn't for the first-time work regulator and there's more than just
...there's very much the people community aspect to it how you interact with people actually being
on get being responsive to...important part of it and I think that's something that everybody has to learn
...their own how that works because also every project slightly different communities
a slightly different and that's one of the other reasons why I think the foundation is such a great ideas because you
bring all these projects together and microsoft as a huge company we had some
pieces of microsoft that are some people microsoft that really new ought to do open-source
... every team that doesn't open-source now I guess what the same learning experience
...benefit tremendously from interacting with the other projects I...been...virtuoso whether...team,
for example, because we opensource roughly the same time frame and there's lots of challenges around that and
I think just bringing people together and seeing you know,
what's happening that's I think a big thing to make the project successful.
And,...kind of...to...projects that's the thing was just lots of learning...need to do
...mentoring around teams it's not just being an engineer...being a social...
...really bad is it all social engineering and software and
...half the time so let's pretend...making a brand-new open-source project
...buzz yet it's a very important enterprise ready
application-level build and I'm like I put on
get hub it's open and it's people are
...pick-up what...the actual process look like a...joy
you dot abpfoundation are like you guys evaluated by come to you as a like
...first day we're trying to fill each other you know, I'm saying...
I've...these people...dot org...
Data so...like really...
What is a process like...dot abpfoundation...dots...the
...and...you know,...have any now let's talk about, you know, if this stuff that we can
provide...and then what what's the what those services about what you going to get out from
the if you're if you're, you know, doing...and your open-source maybe not maybe,
you know, but, we'll still help promote you
...still help promote makes all theopensource is accessible to people and you get hold of things
...every dot net application wants to convince you that foundation
is more about your...need some help scaling the need some...support is
a services...can provide...where can we help yet a lot of times what happens we'll see,
you know, it's the first...contact us right...most talk about they let's
...about your...what you're trying to accomplish with it right a lot of times it's, you know,
we have a lot of them from internal teams that jan bright where they kone open-source...great let's have a
...what licensing thinking about...inI don't know
...good great okay,...governs model you think about I don't know how, you know, so,
how are you going to maintain...about sustaining the project...things and,
we help them kind of map out that strategy so that when
they open-source they have a good experience and they had their set up to actually...
...surviving enrolling in that kind of environment
got it we gotta make sure that these projects are ready to...that's the whole idea you will take projects
are like okay you go...open-source I'm leaving...the...unique
...of...dot net foundation compared to some other ones is that we
don't have one way that things have to be done right we don't have one license that
...we say all projects most...we have a few that we
...we have a few that we do not recommend we actually wouldn't allow project
in...it part of our goal is we want we want...projects that are both great
for open-source community but also for commercial interest as well right so
...a couple license...that are just not good for commercial...regularize that
...adoption of...we think that the best way to get a
...adoption of your open-source project is to have they permissive open-source license
...and especially with the rise of the...with the rise of the internet the most successful
...projects...be the...license ones and you rely on the network effects
...the internet gives you that you bring contribution bat so there's a question does
...dot abpfoundation have open-source licenses that they recommend most you kind of alluded to that
...licensees that are good what are the ones are bad and why do we make this excites
you look at the projects we have today there are there are there are two licenses that are the common ones that
...see today there's the mit license that's one after that as microsoft we've been using that as
are more preferred one lately because it's just simple with...
if straightforward easy-to-understand all caps yet me...the
apache licenses the other one...often...permissive licensees both very explicit
...you and we do have some...projects that...but
...kind of the free may licensees we have right now what are the ones that you
wouldn't take and why I know that's a hard question but I want to...
One of the...what one of the reasons us like we...make sure these projects have a future
rate so we would not take a project if it looks like it's going to be
abandoned on a diet so what we also leads we need to project to be and prop
si approved open-source license...again email talks about the past in the past
we kind of how to cook a licensees like microsoft...which is it's not
...open is...and, I am...on...one could argue it's not it's
...opensource license rights because it because it says thing you have my
...a closes it like you can only use it on windows without
...what...projects those projects and...if you can only easy
...research purposes or academic pepsi's that project is
not allowed in the foundation you have to be a true open-source project...foundation...so here's a
here's a good question I think will bring into relieve what the dot abpfoundation does and
doesn't do the question is how do you validate fixes submitted we provided
test battery to verify the fix it before
...contributes submits the face and I think this is a good question to clarify
...dot abpfoundation does and what they don't do so yet is
...ought to the project leads and ask them what they do for that project so you...ae
...a project...the core...area what would you feel project so what we do on almost
all our projects now as we have a-c isis which basically means...irksome database usually
si system is you submit some...magic happens in the way it works and
open sources that you set it up in such a way that even if you submitted pr you pr subject
to this ci system and what we do a microsoft as we have a long history of like
gazillion tasks why we have...were complicated scenarios we have into an infrastructure that does
...testing and crazy other stuff that we do and
...to get meaningful test...we don't want to gave, you know,
just all the tests as...system because they...wait for like three weeks before we get an answer from the
...by the same time you want to get like, you know, what are the actual meaningful test that we should one obviously
units as a part of that simple stuff input output checks and then, you know,
this thing turns green minutiae services that's fine but there's obviously so the human component
as...look at the actual code and see whether that, you know, the...is well-written whether it's,
you know,...sly guys that we have...there's publicly documented indians
point even better...document actually have a tool that you just run over your cordon
is turns it into what we consider the...guide got it and then there's
a whole other aspects to it just...the design sound...like the api is that your submitted do we think
the resulted useable and that's very subjective to...processes wide about it
...project thing done it on a...and I think it's important to the of there's a very?
Fine line between what the dot...foundation does and what the...so
you're answering as a team lead of an open-source project within the dot
net foundation but there's no prescription
...project well-designed exactly I mean we recommend you probably want to have a
build sever because it makes it easy for people to validate that changes when they come in and know
...is of a project you probably want you know, we definitely want use pool requests,
you know, to...those...question have adobe recommendations not...not...
We want these project to be successful so part of that means that if you're
...contributions the person making a contribution needs to be
confident that it's going to be successful contribution it's not going to break things so you need to
have that enough of that infrastructure place so they can run tasks and competently submit,
you know, from their side before even it hits, you know,...human to look at how you do it as an out,
you know, ...of the problems in open sourcing
still from microsoft is the conscious...is going to visual studio...a random, you know,
retail build windows and just...
Unfortunately not many of oscillations were like that right so you go to
is really easy for people to pick up and build do you have instructions on how to build the
average stokes and how to contribute that's where we give recommendations I actually think
that cortex and...still are they do really good job of saying hey
here the things we label that are up for grabs so
...that...engineers could totally do these things probably super-fast in their sleep
...actually giving like, you know,
these kind of low-hanging fruit to the community so that they can get started easily and get the
...I think measure brilliant idea around
...in general I think the foundation wants to have healthy projects and how
...something that is very subjective to whatever
...your project...right I mean there's geller practices that are establish like you
...people on get up and actually be responsive you don't want to have this, you know,
once a year this is one guy that goes with a good hub for requests and says yep, no,
yes, yep,...you want to have a continuous development happening on...so there's
no prescription that,... you should check it up every five minutes so but the expectation for
...project is you-are-there right it's not just this thing they do every once in awhile and I think
once you go down that path there's a whole bunch of things that come with that it's not just ci...is not just
...request but there's just how do you interact with the community and how do you deal with
that and it's not about code contributions either
...you contribute like you can be a contributor you don't have to write code on the...our I can't
read that project but I can go in and I could say hey maybe file bug
...documentation you can buy only do...the fact that...you can do give general
...immunity...that's exactly right so here's a good question which I think it's kind of interesting one how
would you handle and open-source project which need some close source third-party libraries
...something that you would take or not take we probably wouldn't say I mean
we'd have to work with...to see how we can how somebody who doesn't have the license to
the library would work now is different
if that closed library is library that exist on different platforms, you know, so?
If you thinking about, you know,
what about if you're using some controls some...by vendor than that probably not going
to make sense...if thisbecause you're calling into a cryptography api that
...windows in a different wellness on...linux what makes sense because somebody can
...project...guy would have to talk to them...that we that situation we have yet but, yeah,
...would have to just work with...project and figure out if there's...needs
unique orient everybody needs...take up project...build out so you
mentioned something interesting as I have a little...stuff that I put up...that people started to pull
requests are get hub you talk about governance model what does
that mean for someone that just stuck something up on get up and now people actually
are using it and are try to pull request what's the governance models you suggest and how do
...open-source robbers think about...I'll start with just what is what is the role of the governs model for the
project is basically part of what makes and open-source project successful is
that it is completely open and transparent including how are you deciding what
...requests you're going to accept how you deciding what direction the
projects going to go well that's what the governance model determines its like you
art particularly how...going to work is...dictator like there's one person like, you know,
python is...writing my...because I say ninety there's lots of...so you
can chat about just a modulatory...of...models where it's likeboating base system,
you know, so, if you...you have to...so many like...ones and,
you know, some becomes with the minus one that it needs it and not going to
oreo lodging exactly...lots of different ways that people can run we, you know,
it's recommendations who's in charge of your project you-know-who do I go contact if I
...to...are you going to respond to...requests how do I contribute is basically set
expectations you want to status certain set of expectations up for the project so that people
know-how to contribute...I would just add that if you just start of open-source
I wouldn't think necessarily that is all complicated and have to make all these decisions
up-front one thing that often happens is you just one open-source something library as, you know,
some sort of size is one of step into this new quickly find out what works and what doesn't work for
you don't have to...make all decisions up-front
...you often seen open-source which I think is generally interesting governments model is that
because, you know, if you look at get up and get in particular the whole system is designed to be distributed
so essentially people vote by the fact that...for your
corpus and do something interesting with what you see in the next, for example, is that, you know,
jelly would say there's...benevolent dictator linus...decide what goes in and what doesn't and sometimes he says I don't want
to take this particular patch over here and then when he finds that many of
...other people that he pulls from actually take that patch so...I just okay everybody thinks
it's a good thing I was probably wrong right so that's another thing that I think generally
versus that, you know, people will experimental on and you don't
really know what the right thing is from the get-go and you can change your mind along the way
...so I mean there's not necessarily there's one more ledges for to the lehrer anything stinging
...stocks gaining its...ganging you are in charge...project when
...big needs...skating and have...somebody else...to be a commits on your
...so...an interesting question here from garish what if someone makes
a dot net project it's kind of scroll the bottom...someone makes a dot...that's in the
...they for kitt a commercializing that's also?
...and that's the thing like if you do not if you want to commercialize
it that's great my sense is that you do...assess because look I love machine learning
...machine learning library primarily because I wanted to understand better and I stuck it up so the people that look at
and tell me all your dumb here you did this but that's okay but you want to commercialize it maybe you should open
...about no depends...let's here I this is interesting...
so, ...of all as far as foundations concern if somebody goes and takes
that stuff we are concerned...david hits your terms of a license
...so you need to respect the terms of the...license if a...if
...license says you can take this is language in a
spin around in circles and say half the time sense of...he says you have to give any
changes...code back you have to do that so we help make sure people...terms your license
dot most of our licensees say take it these that...yet so,
that free to just take in commercialize
...one now having a business model that relies on top of
opensource is again that's...to use...the business model we write your
...microsoft business model is, you know, what we can monetize in different ways you can like
so-you windows boxes we can buy you so you services imagine that's how we
like pay for the development of our stuff but other people have different ways people would sell
a content management system but sell the consulting services based
on top of that content management system...now more popular rise more people are using it so just to wrap
up...where can people go to find out more to see if this is something they want to form
...of dot net foundation docile and
...the important...question I don't think we know the answer to the...we're
...work on that so we have like thirty seconds left what
projects are you most interested in the...that sort of strike you as a developer the...like?
I honestly I exif the first-time I saw
...foundation...part of the didn't know about so I would just encourage everybody to just
of the list and make-up your mind like I'm very bias...to get
...recommendation but there's something in for everybody I would think it's true all right
...thanks so much for spending some time with us take a look at
...dot net foundation dot org we will be back after the break see you next time.